Guide to the The Nick Zedd Papers 1963 - 2010 MSS.311
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series II: Projects, 214734
  - Subseries C: Interviews, 214750
    - "Living/Performing/Filming Transgression" by Nicholas Zurbrugg for Art and Design Number 49 [Manuscript with Journal], November 10, 1995; 215304 (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - "Making Totally Depraved Movies: Nick Zedd's Cinema of Transgression" by Alexander Laurence for Cups Issue 80 [Magazine], April 1997; 215305 (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - "Nick Zedd" by Lone Ildgruben for Aspects [Zine, Norway], c1993; 215306 (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - "Nick Zedd" by Nick Zedd, Jack Sargeant, Bob Smith, and Katrina Del Mar for Chaotic Order Number 9 [Zine], 2000; 215307 (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - "Nick Zedd" for Slambook Number 2 [Zine], 1986; 215308 (Box 7, Folder 50)
    - "Nick Zedd Ain't Dead" for Crimson Celluloid Number 8 [Zine], undated; 215309 (Box 7, Folder 51)
    - "Nick Zedd Alive and Well" for BB Gun Number 4 [Magazine], c1998; 215310 (Box 7, Folder 52)
    - "Nick Zedd Confesses on Celluloid" by Mike Black for Gutter Trash Volume 1, Number 3 [Zine], c1992; 215311 (Box 7, Folder 53)
    - "Nick Zedd" for Culture Post-Mortem [Zine, Amsterdam], c1988; 215312 (Box 7, Folder 54)
    - "Nick Zedd Interview" for Bibel [Magazine, Sweden], October 1999; 215313 (Box 7, Folder 55)
    - "Nick Zedd Interview" for Flashback Number 2 [Magazine, Sweden], April 1994; 215314 (Box 7, Folder 56)
    - "Nick Zedd Interview" for Kino-Pravda Hebdomadaire Number 24 [Zine, Switzerland], undated; 215315 (Box 7, Folder 57)
    - "Nick Zedd Interview" for La Repubblica XL [Magazine, Italy], October 2006; 215316 (Box 7, Folder 58)
    - "Nick Zedd Interview" by Jasmine Sailing for Cyber Psycho's A.O.D. Number 3 [Zine], 1993; 215317 (Box 7, Folder 59)
    - "Nick Zedd Interview" by Mark Doucet for Subterrenea Issue 7 [Zine], 1991; 215318 (Box 7, Folder 60)
    - "The Nick Zedd Interview, Part 1" by Mike Black for Gutter Trash Number 1 [Manuscript with Zine], November 2, 1986; 215319 (Box 7, Folder 61)
    - "Nick Zedd Interview" by Neil for Dirt Number 4 [Zine], Fall 1992; 215320 (Box 7, Folder 62)
    - "Nick Zedd Interview" by Nick Walker [Incomplete], December 17, 2000; 215321 (Box 7, Folder 63)
    - "Nick Zedd Interview" for Pussy! Number 12 [Zine], c2003; 215322 (Box 7, Folder 64)
    - "Nick Zedd Interview" for Rage [Magazine, Norway], c1994; 215323 (Box 7, Folder 65)
    - "Nick Zedd Interview" by Sic Mic and Barb Morrison for Lowlife: Rock Magazine Number 10 [Zine], 1986; 215324 (Box 7, Folder 66)
    - "Nick Zedd the Interview: You Talkin' to Me?" by Jay Bliznick for The 1996 Chicago Underground Film Festival [Program Magazine], 215325 (Box 7, Folder 67)
    - "Nick Zedd: Master of Transgression" by Dirk de Bruyn, c1989; 215326 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - "Nick Zedd: What He Said" by T.R. Loviscek for Graffiti Volume 4, Number 7, c1987; 215327 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - "Nick Zedd's Not Dead" for Lollygag Number 3 [Zine], 2009; 215328 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - "Night of the Living Zedd: Underground Filmmaker Confuses Whitmyre" by William Lindsey, February 27, 2006; 215329 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - "Number One With a Bolex: Beyond the Myth of Nick Zedd" by Gene Suicide for Sex & Guts Issue 2 [Manuscript with Zine], 1997 - 1998; 215330 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - "The Only Interview with Nick Zedd That Doesn't Mention Lydia Lunch" by Zietgiest for Kinder & Gentler, c1990; 215331 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - "Prattfolio Alumni Newsmakers: Nick Zedd" [Magazine], Fall 1999; 215332 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - "The Problem with Nick" by Billski for Snack [Zine], March 30, 1986; 215333 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - "Raising the Zedd: An Interview with Nick Zedd" by David E. Williams, undated; 215334 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - "Rattling Around Inside Zedd's Head" by Carmen Vendelin for Blimp Number 35, c1995; 215335 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - "Return of the Living Zedd" by Jenny Gonzalez and Lisa Darrow-Badavi for Brutarian Number 35, 2000; 215336 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - "Richard Kern and Nick Zedd Are Two Sick Fuckers" by Barry Sublapse for Unsound [Manuscript], c1986; 215337 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - "The Sprinkle Salon: Nick Zedd - Filmmaker, Lovemaker, Soultaker" by Annie Sprinkle for Adam Volume 34, Number 1 [Magazine], January 1990; 215338 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - "Today's Pornography is Tomorrow's Art: An Interview with Nick Zedd" by Bob Moricz for NY Waste, November 2000; 215339 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - "Transgressing Cinema: Going to Hell with Nick Zedd" by Carmen Vendelin, April 1996; 215340 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - "Underground Filmmaker Nick Zedd" by Jeri Rossi for Recreational Vehicle: Ego Issue, Spring 1989; 215341 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - "Underground Hedonist: Nick Zedd" by Annie Sprinkle for All Men [Magazine], May 1991; 215342 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - [Untitled Interview Transcript], c1999; 215343 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - "Who Started the Rumors of Your Death and Why?" [Interview Transcript], c1992; 215344 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - "Yours Cruelly, Nick Zedd" in Dead Meat Issue 1 [Zine], 1987; 215345 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - "A Zedd and Two Naughts: Canada Does It to Nick Zedd" by Kieran Mahon for Cannibal Culture Issue 3 [Zine], Fall 1998; 215346 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - "Zedd is Not Dead" by Hugh Gallagher for Draculina Number 12 [Zine], 1991; 215347 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - "Zedd is Not Dead: The Whys and Wares of Nick Zedd" by Jay Sosnicki for Nuthing Sacred Number 5 [Manuscript and Zine], September 1992; 215348 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Subseries D: Ads, Reviews and Literature, 214751
    - "The Adventures of Electra Elf" [Press], 2003 - 2006; 215349 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Bleed [Press], 1992 - 1993; 215350 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - "The Cinema of Transgression" by Ernie Birk for ZAT: 1st Anniversary Issue Number 5 [Manuscript and Magazine], 1985; 215351 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - "Cinema of Transgression Parts 1 and 2" by Cricket Delembard for Draculina Numbers 13 -14 [Zines], 1992; 215352 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - [Cinema of Transgression Press], various; 215353 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - [Cinema of Transgression - International Press], various; 215354 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - "Cinema of Transgression" for Offrande Number 6 [Magazine, France], October - November 1994; 215355 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - "Cinema of Transgression" for Rage [Magazine, Norway], c1992; 215356 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - "Cinema Underground USA" for Decoder Number 3 [Magazine, Italy], c1987; 215357 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - "Geek Maggot Bingo" [Press], c1983; 215358 (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Goteborg Poetry Art Festival [Press, Sweden], 1988; 215359 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - "Lord of the Cockrings" [Press], 2002; 215360 (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - "Nick Zedd Eulogy" for Ben is Dead: Black Issue Number 24, Summer 1994; 215361 (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - [Nick Zedd International Press Pack], 1990; 215363 (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - "No Such Thing as Gravity" by Alyce Wittenstein [Press], c1990; 215362 (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - "Notes on the Work of Nick Zedd" by Jonas Mekas [Manuscript], undated; 215364 (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - "Police State" [Press], c1991; 215365 (Box 8, Folder 40)
    - "Screen Tests" [Press], 1998; 215366 (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - "Shadows in the City" by Ari Roussimoff [Press], c1991; 215367 (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - "Thrust in Me" [Press], 1984 - 1986; 215368 (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - "Thus Spake Zarathustra" [Press], 2001; 215369 (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - "Sex 'n Violence and Music: NY Underground Film" for Journal Film Number 17 [Magazine, Germany], August - September 1988; 215370 (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - "They Eat Scum" [Press], various; 215371 (Box 8, Folder 46)
    - Totem of the Depraved [Press], c1991; 215372 (Box 8, Folder 47)
    - Underground Film Bulletin [Press], various; 215373 (Box 8, Folder 48)
    - "Underground Film Made in U.S.A." for Filmfaust [Magazine, Germany], October - November 1988; 215374 (Box 8, Folder 49)
    - "War is Menstrual Envy" [Press], various; 215375 (Box 8, Folder 50)
    - "Whoregasm" [Press], various; 215376 (Box 8, Folder 51)
    - [Zedd Ads], various; 215377 (Box 8, Folder 52)
    - [Book Excerpts Featuring Zedd], various; 215378 (Box 8, Folder 53)
    - If We Die Without Jesus We Shall Go to Hell [Zine], c1993; 215379 (Box 8, Folder 54)
    - Subversion: The Definitive History of Underground Cinema by Duncan Reekie [Manuscript], 2007; 215380 (Box 8, Folder 55)
  - Subseries E: Other Artists and Events, 214752
    - The Armory Show, New York Pier 92, 2010; 215381 (Box 8, Folder 56)
    - Artists Space: Remapping Boundaries, March 14 - May 4, 1991; 215382 (Box 8, Folder 57)
    - 12th Asian American International Film Festival [French Institute, NY], 1989; 215383 (Box 8, Folder 58)
    - "Betaville" by Alyce Wittenstein [Pocket Press Kit], 1988; 215384 (Box 8, Folder 59)
    - "Blonde Death" [Press Materials], 1983; 215385 (Box 8, Folder 60)
    - Brooklyn Arts and Culture Association, Inc. [Newsletters 8 - 9], 1984 - 1985; 215386 (Box 8, Folder 61)
    - "Buffalo '66" by Vincent Gallo [Press Pack], 1998; 215387 (Box 8, Folder 62)
    - "Cecil B. Demented" by John Waters [Screening Program], 2000; 215388 (Box 8, Folder 63)
    - 6th Annual Chicago Underground Film Festival [Program], 1999; 215389 (Box 8, Folder 64)
    - Chicago Underground Film Fest [Program], undated; 215390 (Box 8, Folder 65)
    - "Every Minute as We Are Talking Films Are Falling to Dust" [Anthology Films Archives Program], c1992; 215391 (Box 8, Folder 66)
    - Exposure Future of Film Fest [New York Program], August 4 - 5, 2000; 215392 (Box 8, Folder 67)
    - [Flyers], various; 215393 (Box 8, Folder 68)
    - "Highway of Heartache" by Gregory Wild [Press Pack], 1994; 215394 (Box 8, Folder 69)
    - "Kenneth Anger's Icons" [Courthouse Gallery, Anthology Film Archives Program], January 30 - March 2, 1996; 215395 (Box 8, Folder 70)
    - "Kinetica 2: Centennial Tribute to Oskar Fischinger" [Program], 2000; 215396 (Box 8, Folder 71)
    - 1st Los Angeles International Film Exposition [Programs], November 4 - 14, 1971; 215397 (Box 8, Folder 72)
    - "Marcel Marceau with Pierre Verry" [Academy of Music Philadelphia Program], March 28 - 29, 1976; 215398 (Box 8, Folder 73)
    - Metro Con [University of Maryland, Program], November 23 - 24, 1973; 215399 (Box 8, Folder 74)
    - Millennium Film Workshop Spring Series [Program], 1995; 215400 (Box 8, Folder 75)
    - "Multiple Futures and Other Paranoid Fantasies" by Alyce Wittenstein [Press Pack], 1995; 215401 (Box 8, Folder 76)
    - Museum of African American History and Arts: Black Film Festival [Program], June 1991; 215402 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - One Arm Red [Brooklyn, NY Calendar], Spring / Summer 2004; 215403 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Preview: Program Guide to AFI Theater and Member Events, August 1991; 215404 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - "Super 8 Motel" [Lydia Lunch, Richard Kern Program], c1985; 215405 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - "Superstar: The Karen Carpenter Story" by Todd Haynes [Screening Program], 1987; 215406 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Swedish Avant Garde Film, 1924 - 1990 [Program], 215407 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - "Warp One: My Battlefield, My Body" [Ambassador Theatre Playbill Magazine], February 1973; 215408 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - "Warp: The World's First Science Fiction Epic Adventure Play in Serial Form" [Trinity Theatre, Washington DC Program], undated; 215409 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Series III: Correspondence, 214735
  Series III: Correspondence preserves communication not directly related to any single production, and is organized alphabetically by individual or company in contact, then chronologically.
  Subseries A: Professional
  Subseries B: Personal
  - Subseries A: Professional, 214753
    - [Allin, GG], c1988; 215410 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - [Biafra, Jello], undated; 215411 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - [British Film Institute], 1997 - 2003; 215413 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - [Professional Film Distribution], 1982 - 2010; 215414 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - [Film Threat], 1986, 1992 - 1996; 215415 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - [Freeland - Hughes, Tessa], 1986; 215416 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - [Genocide, Gia], 1983 - 1985; 215417 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - [Jacobson and Colfin, P.C.], 1995, 2005; 215418 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - [Kern, Richard], 1988; 215419 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - [Lunch, Lydia], 1983 - 1987; 215420 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - [Museum of Modern Art], 1988 - 1989, 1996 - 2001; 215421 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - [Nick Zedd Fan Club Mailing List], undated; 215422 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - [Pekar, Harvey], 1985; 215423 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - [Penetration Films], various; 215424 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - [Pfahler, Kembra], 1989, 1991; 215425 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - [Press Correspondence], various; 215426 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - [Professional Writing Correspondence], 1989 - 2000; 215427 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - [Saint Reverend Jen / Electra Elf], 2002 - 2005; 215428 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - [Underground Film Bulletin], various; 215429 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - [Video.com], 1996 - 1997; 215430 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - [Whitney Museum of Art], 1996, 1998; 215431 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - [Waters, John], various; 215432 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Subseries B: Personal, 214754
    - [1970s Personal Correspondence], 1972, 1977; 215438 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - [1980s Personal Correspondence], 1980 - 1989; 215433 (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - [1990s Personal Correspondence, 1 of 2], 1990 - 1999; 215434 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - [1990s Personal Correspondence, 2 of 2], 1990 - 1999; 215435 (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - [2000s Personal Correspondence], 2000 - 2010; 215436 (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - [Undated Personal Correspondence], 215437 (Box 9, Folder 36)
- Series IV: Dad's Pornography Collection, 214736
  Series IV: Dad's Pornography Collection preserves Zedd's father's work as a United States Postal Service censorship researcher. This series is arranged alphabetically by subject and document type.
  - "Censorship - Propaganda - Post Office Dept.", 1959 - 1963; 215439 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - "Contemporary Community Standards" [Assorted Clippings], 1960 - 1964; 215440 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - "Esquire Style Drawings: The Betty Girl Revue", 1937 - 1938; 215442 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - [Lady Chatterly Articles], c1962; 215441 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - [Mail Order Pornography], 1959 - 1961; 215443 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - "Obscenity: Articles and Background Material for Speaking, Research, Etc.", 1969 - 1970; 215446 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - [Pamphlets], 1955 - 1966; 215447 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - [Pornographic Photographs], undated; 215448 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Series V: Photography, 214737
  Series V: Photography contains photographs, contact sheets, negatives, and slides pertaining to Zedd's productions and personal collection.
  - Subseries A: Professional, 214755
    - "The Giant Fly Invincible" by Nick Zedd [film strip], 1969; 214909 (Box Binder 1)
    - "Nomad" by Nick Zedd, 1978; 216657 (Box Binder 1)
    - "They Eat Scum" by Nick Zedd [Includes other work with Donna Death], 1979; 214910 (Box Binder 1)
    - "They Eat Scum" by Nick Zedd [Includes other work with Donna Death], 1979; 214903 (Box Binder 2)
    - "The Bogus Man" by Nick Zedd, 1980; 214904 (Box Binder 2)
    - "Geet Maggot Bingo" by Nick Zedd, 1983; 214905 (Box Binder 2)
    - "The Wild World of Lydia Lunch" by Nick Zedd, 1983; 214906 (Box Binder 2)
    - "Kiss Me Goodbye" by Nick Zedd, 1985; 214907 (Box Binder 2)
    - "Johnny Satan" by Nick Zedd, c1986; 214908 (Box Binder 2)
    - "King of Sex" by Richard Kern, 1986; 214899 (Box Binder 3)
    - "King of Sex" by Richard Kern [Mounted Still], 1986; 215449 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - "Police State" by Nick Zedd, 1987; 214900 (Box Binder 3)
    - "Whoregasm" by Nick Zedd [Includes other work with Susan Manson], c1988; 214901 (Box Binder 3)
    - "Nick Zedd" by Annie Sprinkle, January 1990; 215450 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - "War is Menstrual Envy" by Nick Zedd, 1992; 214902 (Box Binder 3)
    - "Trilogy of Teri" by Kembra Pfahler, c1990; 214890 (Box Binder 4)
    - "Shadows in the City" by Ari Roussimoff, 1990; 214891 (Box Binder 4)
    - "Screen Tests / Why Do You Exist" by Nick Zedd, 1998; 214892 (Box Binder 4)
    - "Screen Tests / Why Do You Exist" [Stills], 1998; 215452 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - "Ecstasy in Entropy" by Nick Zedd, 1999; 214893 (Box Binder 4)
    - "Ecstasy in Entropy" by Nick Zedd, 1999; 215451 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - "Tom Thumb in the Land of Giants" by Nick Zedd, 1999; 214894 (Box Binder 4)
    - "Thus Spake Zarathustra" by Nick Zedd, 2001; 214895 (Box Binder 4)
    - "The Adventures of Electra Elf" by Saint Reverend Jen and Nick Zedd, 2002 - 2008; 214896 (Box Binder 4)
    - "The Adventures of Electra Elf", 2003; 215453 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - [Miscellaneous Production Images], various; 214897 (Box Binder 4)
    - [Modeling and Press, 1 of 2], various; 214898 (Box Binder 4)
    - [Modeling and Press, 2 of 2], various; 214888 (Box Binder 5)
  - Subseries B: Personal, 214756
    - [Miscellaneous Talent and Social Events], 214887 (Box Binder 6)
    - [Unidentified Female Nude], undated; 215454 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Series VI: Illustrations and Artwork, 214738
  Series VI: Illustrations and Artwork includes Zedd's original comic illustrations and paintings.
  - Spring Intramurals Flyer, 1977; 215455 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - [Sketches Removed from "Johnny Satan" Sketchbook], undated; 215456 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - [Gia Genocide Illustrations], January 1985; 215457 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - [Illustrations of Richard Hell for Underground Film Bulletin], c1985; 215458 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - "A Collection of Original Collages" by Nick Zedd, 1987 - 1990; 219627 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    General
    This collection includes 8 collages by Nick Zedd and a description by John McWhinnie.
  - [Males in Logos], undated; 215459 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - [New York Marlon Brando Painting], undated; 215460 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - "Aber Otto" by Kurt Kren, 1974; 215461 (Box 10, Folder 17)
- Series VII: Objects, 214739
  Series VII: Objects contains an assortment of props and production materials, Zedd-Casanova Clothing, and "The Mexican Kit."
  Subseries A: Props
  Subseries B: Zedd - Casanova Clothing includes a variety of tops and pleated skirts featuring prints from Zedd's filmography, and the original screenprint stencils. Designed by Nick Zedd and his wife Monica Casanova.
  Subseries C: The Mexican Kit is an assortment of personal items Zedd collectively titled "The Mexican Kit." This assemblage includes a miniature piñata, ornaments, household adornments, sugar skulls, and figurines.
  - Subseries A: Props, 215533
    - [Eye Glasses], undated; 215474 (Box 11, Object ID: 311.2.0001)
    - [Gory Cut-Off Arm], undated; 215471 (Box 11, Object ID: 311.2.0002)
    - "Blood Thirst Quencher Gourmet Meat Seed" [Small Duncan Hines Container], undated; 215475 (Box 11, Object ID: 311.2.0003)
    - "Blood Thirst Quencher Gourmet Meat Seed" [Oversized Plastic Utz Jar], undated; 215473 (Box 11, Object ID: 311.2.0004)
    - Emile Durkheim's Suicide [used for "Thrust in Me"], 1984; 215462 (Box 10, Object ID: 311.2.0005, Folder 18)
    - "The Adventures of Electra Elf" Press Passes, undated; 215463 (Box 10, Object ID: 311.2.0006, Folder 19)
    - Kodak Brownie Movie Camera [Model 2, Number 76], undated; 215479 (Box 11, Object ID: 311.2.0007)
    - Hollywood Film Co. Film Reel Metal Container, undated; 215478 (Box 11, Object ID: 311.2.0008)
    - [Film Production Clapboard], undated; 215480 (Box 11, Object ID: 311.2.0009)
    - [Small Ceramic Face Sculpture], undated; 215476 (Box 11, Object ID: 311.2.0010)
    - [Punk Doll], undated; 215477 (Box 11, Object ID: 311.2.0011)
      This object was originally found with the Zedd - Casanova Clothing Designs.
    - [John Waters Pen], undated; 215470 (Box 11, Object ID: 311.2.0012)
- Series VIII: Film, 214740
  Conditions Governing Access
  Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
  Series VIII: Film includes original filmic elements by Zedd and is organized chronologically, then alphabetically.
  Subseries A: By Nick Zedd
  Subseries B: Original Containers
  Subseries C: Juvenelia and Family include films Zedd completed as a youth, in addition to a collection of Harding Family movies.
  Subseries D: Miscellaneous includes Lung Leg's "Worm Movie" and a collection of commercial films from Zedd's personal collection.
  Subseries E: Film Documentation includes laboratory forms found with Zedd's original works.
  - Subseries A: By Nick Zedd, 214757
    - "Destination X - A Roll", 1976; ID: 311.0003; 215569 (Media Shelf, Media ID: 311.0003)
      Format: 16mm
      TRT: [unknown]
    - "Nomad", c1978; ID: 311.0004; 215570 (Media Shelf, Media ID: 311.0004)
    - "They Eat Scum - Spliced Original Reel 1 of 2", 1979; ID: 311.0006; 215571 (Media Shelf, Media ID: 311.0006)
      Format: Super 8mm
    - "They Eat Scum - Spliced Original Reel 2 of 2", 1979; ID: 311.0007a; 215572 (Media Shelf, Media ID: 311.0007a)
    - "They Eat Scum - Spliced Original Reel 2 of 2", 1979; ID: 311.0007b; 216754 (Media Shelf, Media ID: 311.0007b)
      Format: Super 8
    - "They Eat Scum - Outtakes", 1979; ID: 311.0008; 215573 (Media Shelf, Media ID: 311.0008)
    - "The Bogus Man", 1980; ID: 311.0002a; 215564 (Media Shelf, Media ID: 311.0002a)
      Originally found with 311.0002b: "Skeleton - Nick Zedd."
    - "Skeleton - Nick Zedd", 1980; ID: 311.0002b; 215565 (Media Shelf, Media ID: 311.0002b)
      Removed from 311.0002a: "The Bogus Man" Print. This was possibly used as leader.
    - "Geek Maggot Bingo - Pix Trk 1 of 4", 1983; ID: 311.0009; 215574 (Media Shelf, Media ID: 311.0009)
      TRT: unknown
    - "Geek Maggot Bingo - Trk", 1983; ID: 311.0010; 215575 (Media Shelf, Media ID: 311.0010)
    - [Geek Maggot Bingo - Unlabeled], 1983; ID: 311.0011; 215576 (Media Shelf, Media ID: 311.0011)
    - "Geek Maggot Bingo - R1 Color Positive", 1983; ID: 311.0012; 215578 (Media Shelf, Media ID: 311.0012)
    - "Geek Maggot Bingo - R1 Opt. Trk Tail", 1983; ID: 311.0013; 215577 (Media Shelf, Media ID: 311.0013)
    - "Geek Maggot Bingo - R3 Opt Trk Head", 1983; ID: 311.0014; 215579 (Media Shelf, Media ID: 311.0014)
    - "Geek Maggot Bingo - R3 Pos Rev Color w/Mag Sound, 'B'-Wind Pix", 1983; ID: 311.0015; 215580 (Media Shelf, Media ID: 311.0015)
    - "The Wild World of Lydia Lunch - Original", 1984; ID: 311.0016; 215581 (Media Shelf, Media ID: 311.0016)
    - "Police State - Fill", 1987; ID: 311.0026; 215660 (Media Shelf, Media ID: 311.0026)
    - "Police State - HHKK", 1987; ID: 311.0028; 215662 (Media Shelf, Media ID: 311.0028)
    - "Police State - Scene Two Dailies PIX HD", 1987; ID: 311.0032; 215666 (Media Shelf, Media ID: 311.0032)
    - "Police State - Junk Footage Scene Two", 1987; ID: 311.0033; 215667 (Box Binder 3, Media ID: 311.0033)
    - "Police State - Work Pix Dupe", 1987; ID: 311.0034; 215668 (Media Shelf, Media ID: 311.0034)
    - "Police State - Work Pix HD", 1987; ID: 311.0035; 215669 (Media Shelf, Media ID: 311.0035)
    - "Police State - Nick's Face", 1987; ID: 311.0036; 215670 (Box Binder 3, Media ID: 311.0036)
    - "Police State - Credits", 1987; ID: 311.0037; 215671 (Media Shelf, Media ID: 311.0037)
    - "Police State - Fill" [Unmarked Reel], 1987; ID: 311.0038; 215672 (Media Shelf, Media ID: 311.0038)
    - "Police State - Fill" [Blank], 1987; ID: 311.0039; 215673 (Media Shelf, Media ID: 311.0039)
    - "Police State - Dial A", 1987; ID: 311.0040; 215674 (Media Shelf, Media ID: 311.0040)
    - "Police State - Dial B", 1987; ID: 311.0041; 215675 (Media Shelf, Media ID: 311.0041)
    - "Police State - B-Wind Op. Track Head", c1987; ID: 311.0447; 215644 (Media Shelf, Media ID: 311.0447)
      TRT" [unknown]
    - "Police State - Scene Three Dailies TRK HD", 1987; ID: 311.0051; 215690 (Media Shelf, Media ID: 311.0051)